# **Aria Diamond**

Full Stack Software Developer

#### **PROFILE**

Full stack developer with an emphasis on front-end work. Expert in React and JavaScript, with frequent usage of Ruby and SQL. Strong conceptual understanding of computer fundamentals, such as network protocols, data structures, MVC and their relationship to APIs. Everyday use with modern development strategies like continuous integration, git, and deploying code to dev, staging, and production environments.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer, ListenFirst Media — March 2022—Present

Developed a bulk upload service of content tags, including writing Ruby code inserting into a data warehouse, updating a Rails controller with asynchronous jobs, and writing React code to interact with the File Web API. I am also currently working on a project to build a self-service feature for configuration that currently only exists as an internal tool, and rewriting a legacy application, migrating from Backbone.js and jQuery to React, clarifying state and reducing future dev time.

## Grader, UCSC — October 2020-June 2021

Evaluated students assignments for correctness and gave detailed feedback on mistakes. Worked for three upper division classes: design and analysis of algorithms, computational models, and database management.

## Group Tutor, UCSC — January 2020-April 2020, March 2021-June 2021

Explained assignments and concepts surrounding compilers in Haskell and distributed systems in Go, Python, and JavaScript. Troubleshot code written by students.

## **EDUCATION**

University of California, Santa Cruz — Computer Science B.S., 2018-2021, 3.9 GPA

Graduated Magna Cum Laude and Highest Honors in the major Relevant Coursework: Database Systems 1&2, Distributed Systems, Software Engineering, Functional Programming, Analysis of Algorithms, Data Structures

#### **PROJECTS**

<u>Journal</u> is a ReactNative app (in need of a better name). It is still relatively new, but uses React fundamentals, such as hooks and state, to build a multi-screen application with persistent storage of data. There have been multiple refactors to try to minimize the codebase, including moving back and forth from a hierarchical page structure.

https://github.com/ariadiamond/